"All the world likes an outlaw. For some damn reason
they remember 'em." - Jesse James
The Long Riders is a western, action, crime film directed by Walter Hill.
The origins, exploits and the ultimate fate of the James gang is told in a sympathetic portrayal of the
bank robbers made up of brothers who begin their legendary bank raids because of revenge.
Cole Younger, played by David Carradine.
Jim Younger, played by Keith Carradine.
Bob Younger, played by Robert Carradine.
Jesse James, played by James Keach.
Frank James, played by Stacy Keach.
Ed Miller, played by Dennis Quaid.
The Long Riders is a 1980 American biographical
western film directed by Walter Hill.
It was produced by James Keach, Stacy Keach and Tim Zinnemann
and featured an original soundtrack by Ry Cooder.
Cooder won the Best Music award in 1980 from the Los Angeles Film
Critics Association Awards for this soundtrack.
The film was entered into the 1980 Cannes Film Festival.
The film is notable for having cast four sets of actual brothers to
play the four sets of brothers in the James–Younger Gang.
The film explores themes of sibling relationship, jesse james, cole younger.
The tone is emotional.